<?xml version="1.0"?>
<event-catalog xmlns="EMSEvents-2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" release="R8.3.1xN_150831_0127" vendor="netapp" ontap_version="Fullsteam__8.3.1" xsi:schemaLocation="EMSEvents-2.0 ./ems_2.0.xsd">
  <event-def name="scsiblade.out.of.quorum" severity="EMERG">
		<description>
		    This message occurs when the node has gone out 
		    of SAN quorum. Both FCP and iSCSI traffic have 
		    been disabled on this node.
		</description>
		<corrective-action type="TEXT"> 
		    Reboot the node, and if the node is waiting for giveback then 
		    perform a giveback.
		</corrective-action>
		<syslog facility="LOG_DAEMON">
		    <format>
			This node is no longer in SAN quorum and will not
			provide any SAN service until cluster communications
			are restored.
		    </format>
		</syslog>
	</event-def>
  <event-def name="scsiblade.in.quorum" severity="INFO">
		<description>
		    This message occurs when the scsi-blade on 
		    this node established quorum with the other 
		    nodes in the cluster.
		</description>
		<corrective-action type="NONE"/> 
		<syslog facility="LOG_DAEMON" severity="LOG_INFO">
		    <format>
			The scsi-blade on this node established quorum with the
			other nodes in the cluster.
		    </format>
		</syslog>
	</event-def>
  <event-def name="scsiblade.volume.event.lost" severity="CRIT">
		<description>
		    This message occurs when LUNs in the specified Vserver and 
		    volume might not be accessible or might not be accessible 
		    on all paths.
		</description>
		<param name="volume" type="LONGINTHEX">
		    <description>
			Volume identifier.
		    </description>
		</param>
		<param name="vserver" type="STRING">
		    <description>
			Name or UUID of the Vserver.
		    </description>
		</param>
		<corrective-action type="CALL_SUPPORT"/>
		<syslog facility="LOG_DAEMON">
		    <format>
			Access to LUNs in volume with MSID %llu on Vserver %s 
			has been lost through one or more paths.
		    </format>
		</syslog>
	</event-def>
  <event-def name="scsiblade.consistency.issue" severity="EMERG">
		<description>
		    This message occurs when one or more LUNs in the 
		    specified Vserver may not be accessible or may not 
		    be accessible on all paths.
		</description>
		<corrective-action type="TEXT"> 
		    Perform a planned takeover/giveback.
		</corrective-action>
		<syslog facility="LOG_DAEMON">
		    <format>
			One or more luns in the specified vserver may not be 
			accessible or may not be accessible on all paths.
		    </format>
		</syslog>
	</event-def>
  <event-def name="callhome.ses.drive.missing" severity="NODE_ERROR">
        <description>

	This message occurs when the storage adapter detects a disk on the
        Fibre Channel loop or the SCSI bus, but enclosure services in the
	disk shelf does not report a disk with that address.

	This error indicates that the disk took an address
	other than what the disk shelf should have provided, or that
	enclosure services in the disk shelf cannot be contacted for
	address information.

	(Note: If the message "ses.drive.possShelfAddr" subsequently
	appears, follow the corrective actions in that
	message.)

	In this condition, the SCSI Enclosure Services (SES)
	process in the system might be unable to
	perform certain operations on the disk, such as
	setting failure LEDs or detecting disk swaps.

        If your system is configured to do so, it generates and transmits
        an AutoSupport (or 'call home') message to NetApp technical support
        and to the configured destinations. Successful delivery of an
        AutoSupport message significantly improves problem
        determination and resolution.
        </description>
        <param name="subject" type="STRING">
          <description>
            AutoSupport subject or title for this event.
          </description>
        </param>
        <param name="ChannelName" type="STRING">
	  <description>
	    Channel the disk shelf is on.
	  </description>
	</param>
	<param name="LoopIds" type="STRING">
	  <description>
	    Loop or SCSI IDs of the missing disks.
	  </description>
	</param>
	<corrective-action>
  	  If the disk is not part of an active aggregate or volume, pull
	  out the disk and push it back into the slot to ensure
	  that the disk is in place. If the problem persists, insert a
	  spare disk into the slot. If the problem is then gone,
	  replace the original disk with the spare one.
	  If the problem occurs to multiple disks on the same loop,
	  check the I/O modules at the back of the disk shelves
	  on that loop for errors.
	</corrective-action>
        <syslog>
                <format>
                Call home for SES: DRIVE MISSING
                </format>
        </syslog>

        <asup>
                <reason>SES: DRIVE MISSING</reason>
                <msgno>ASUP_MSG_SES_DRIVE_MISSING</msgno>
                <support content="COMPLETE" timer="300"/>
                <to content="COMPLETE" timer="300"/>
                <note content="PAGER" timer="300"/>
        </asup>

    </event-def>
  <event-def name="cmds.unable.get.valueKey" severity="ERR">
		<description>
			This message occurs when the system can not 
			get the value corresponding to the specified 
			registry key.
		</description>
		<param name="key" type="STRING">
			<description>
				key name.
			</description>
		</param>
		<corrective-action type="NONE"/>
		<deprecated>
			Deprecated as of Data ONTAP 8.3 no longer supported.
		</deprecated>
		<syslog severity="LOG_ERR">
			<format>
				ipspace: Could not get the value for %s.
			</format>
		</syslog>
	</event-def>
</event-catalog>